# Stevo Racković

Data Scientist, Researcher at IST



I work as a machine learning researcher, primarily solving optimization problems in the field of facial animation. Additionally, work on projects that develop Reinforcement Learning for task offloading, and Recommendation Systems for health services. I have great interest in machine learning and deep learning in general, and in particular I am excited about applying cutting-edge technology advances to everyday problems with the goal of improving living standards and easing daily routines.

# Experience

2019-present **Early Stage Researcher**, Institute for Systems and Robotics, Instituto Superior Técnico, Lisbon

- O Partner within TaRDIS Project with NOVA University
  - Research on task offloading in network of machines
  - Developing deep reinforcement learning agents in PyTorch
  - Hands-on experience with Python (PyTorch, NumPy, SciPy, Scikit-Learn, Pandas)
- Research in distributed optimization and machine learning models with application in the animation industry.
- O Cooperation with 3Lateral Studio, Epic Games.
  - Developing custom optimization algorithms in Python
  - Testing in Python and Autodesk Maya
- Part of Marie Curie Actions BIGMATH.

2018–2019 Junior Researcher, Faculty of Sciences, University of Novi Sad, Novi Sad

- Developing models for distributed implementation of the common machine learning algorithms.
  - Working in Python with PyCOMPSs, Scikit-Learn, NumPy
- Part of a team working on IBiDaaS H2020: Industrial-driven big data as a self-service project.

Summer 2017 Intern, BIOSENSE Institute, Novi Sad

- Developing a classifier to accurately recognize the cultures planted in specific fields using satellite images.
  - Deep Convolutional Neural Networks with Keras
- Remote Sensing Lab.

### Education

2019-present PhD in Statistics and Stochastic Processes, Instituto Superior Técnico, Lisbon

- The curriculum covers machine learning, optimization, and statistics with a high demand for both theoretical and practical skills.
- O Thesis: Distributed optimization of biokinetic models based on large 4D sequences.
- The goal is solving large-scale optimization problems in the face animation of video games. The main focus is on a distributed optimization setting for reducing computational costs.

2016–2018 Master in Applied Mathematics, University of Novi Sad, Novi Sad

2013–2016 Bachelors in Applied Mathematics, University of Novi Sad, Novi Sad

# Languages

Serbian Native Speaker

English Fluent

Portuguese Intermediate

## Skills

#### **Technical**

Python with TensorFlow and PyTorch, Microsoft Office, MySQL, Autodesk Maya

## Conceptual

Problem-solving, Machine Learning with deep learning, Data analysis, Optimization, Statistics

### Publications

- "Clustering of the Blendshape Facial Model", S. Racković, C. Soares, D. Jakovetić, Z. Desnica, R. Ljubobratović, 2021, 29th European Signal Processing Conference (EUSIPCO)
- "A Hybrid Compartmental Model with a Case Study of COVID-19 in Great Britain and Israel", G. Malaspina, S. Racković, F. Valdeira, 2023, Journal of Mathematics in Industry
- "A Majorization–Minimization-based Method for Nonconvex Inverse Rig Problems in Facial Animation: Algorithm Derivation", S. Racković, C. Soares, D. Jakovetić, Z. Desnica, 2023, Optimization Letters
- "Distributed Solution of the Blendshape Rig Inversion Problem", S. Racković, C. Soares, D. Jakovetić, 2023, SIGGRAPH Asia 2023 Technical Communications
- "Extreme Multilabel Classification for Specialist Doctor Recommendation with Implicit Feedback and Limited Patient Metadata", F. Valdeira, S. Racković, V. Danalachi, Q. Han, C. Soares